Welcome back.
We are playing the Binding of Isaac.
And I happen to be binding new Isaac's today.
We unlocked a new character Bethany.
Well, it's Bethany but you know it's different somehow.
Minus one hearts.
I don't know how I feel about that.
Weaker items.
Blood power.
The Megaton.
I have no idea what any of that means.
I'm going in.
Dude, I just ripped the biggest burp of all time and I managed to mute just in time.
I'm glad you didn't have to go through that.
You were spared.
I also just ate a piece of candy, so I'm going to be experiencing a sugar rush.
I'm just going to prepare you for that.
It will happen.
Okay, so let me see here.
What's happening right now?
We have an item in the bottom right now.
The Megaton.
It's a book.
Grants an orbital wisp that resembles a random passive item.
While the wisp is alive, Isaac has that item's passive effects.
What?
Wisp steal contact damage to enemies but take damage.
When one is destroyed, its passive item effects are lost.
Huh.
That sounds weird.
Okay.
I just gained some damage.
Do I know what I just got?
I got some kind of wisp.
I got three blue hearts, which is not great.
Also, why do I have red bars on this thing now?
Oh, it's just I have two charges of it, I guess.
Oh, wait, I'm consuming red hearts to do it.
I see that red heart thing on the left now.
Got it.
So it's pretty much like Bethany, but different.
Yeah, I don't know what effect I have now.
These are both like the same wisps it looks like.
Oh my god.
Oh wait, I'm shooting different things here.
I just shot a weird ball.
Let's go this way.
I'm doing decent damage here.
Oh, got charmed.
So I have some kind of charm effect.
Maybe I have that random rainbow effect on right now, you know?
Maybe that would explain why they're, you know, being affected randomly by things.
Rainbow shot or whatever.
It's wait, it's called item summoner when I hold tap.
Makes sense, I guess.
Why call it the Megaton though?
I can't step, not with blue hearts, man.
I can't do it.
This is gonna be tough.
I honestly don't know how to do this.
I think I just have to go for it.
Okay, we got lucky there.
Oh, nice.
That's scary.
We got to destroy these.
These rooms are scary, man.
When you don't have any red hearts.
Oh, nice.
Huge.
A lucky penny as well on top of it all.
Nice.
Even better.
Plus one health.
Oh no, it's not gonna work for me, right?
It's gonna get put into the red heart thingy.
Okay, well, we got a bunch of red hearts out of that.
It's not just one we got.
All right, all right.
Respect.
I'm gonna... Oh my god, it looks like a pair of testicles.
Like, like a necklace.
I can't not see that.
Am I the only one?
I hate the look of it.
Horrible.
Low it up.
Ah, imagine though.
Imagine.
Okay.
I was kind of hoping I would get to see... I was hoping I would get to see the item around me.
And I kind of do, but I thought they were both the same effect, but they're not.
That one is clearly like a mushroom.
So maybe that's why I get the random effects.
It's that the rainbow mushroom or whatever, you know?
It wouldn't explain it.
Also, I'm having trouble speaking today.
I don't know why.
It's one of those days.
Dude, I do good damage here.
So far, this is solid, man.
Do it again.
We got some speed out of that.
I like it.
So far, solid character.
Wait, I have homing now.
Right?
Do I have homing?
No, it was just a random effect.
Okay.
Kind of want to buy this heart.
Simply because, you know, this is my bread and butter right now.
I'm taking it.
Also, I wonder if we're gonna be encountering demons or angels.
Normal Bethany has like angels, right?
But maybe this is like the dark version.
So we're gonna have demons.
I guess we'll see.
Widow.
This guy will always damage me.
I can't avoid this attack.
I'm so bad at the game.
Kind of want to do this again.
Get more range.
Okay, there he goes.
Dude, somehow I'm still... or I'm kind of doing it right now.
Usually I always take damage against this guy.
Nice!
I'm the man.
Proud of myself.
That's progress right there.
Growth hormones?
Hell yeah.
Actually better than... Oh, notice how one of the items I have around me is like a little, what do you call it?
Injection mechanism.
Also called?
You know what I mean.
I can't remember.
Let's go to the... I'm not gonna step.
Nope, no stepping.
But yeah, we're done here.
I don't even know what the plan is.
I guess going home makes no sense.
Or maybe it does.
I don't know.
Like, if I go home, I want to get the key, right?
Oh, I can't get in there.
Need more keys.
Shit!
That got
a little bit frozen.
Nerd.
I don't know if I should just activate as many flies as possible or wisps.
I do also wonder if it's gonna combine with other active items just like normal Bethany, you know?
Boiled baby?
I mean, yeah, okay.
Not a huge fan of that, if I'm honest.
It's not even hitting anything.
That baby, the boiled baby.
Boy, yoy, yoy.
Okay, he did hit a little there.
That's good.
No tinted rocks.
Oh my god, how did I do that?
That was so good.
There we go.
Lock up.
I love it.
Make another fly.
Oh, oh, wait, wait.
It displays the name of the item you get.
It just... I just saw that.
I need to pay attention to what the item is like that I get.
So we got wooden spoon just now.
This room again, huh?
Oi!
Nearly got me there.
Go!
Oh, close one.
Another Fiver place.
Okay.
Still only have one key, so I can't get into the dice room, unfortunately.
Would love to get in there.
We find key here, perhaps?
Oh, the Sun!
It doesn't do much for me, though, other than revealing the map.
You know, healing me is not gonna work, because I have blue hearts.
But I guess I'll use it to heal damage like this and reveal the map.
Okay, not too bad.
So, secret right there.
Only one secret?
Isn't that kind of unheard of?
I don't know if I should go in there.
I can't sacrifice HP for this.
I just can't.
Come on, key, key!
Nice!
Exactly what a man needs.
I'm gonna blow you... Oh, by the way, 100% demon!
There's no angel right now.
So, yeah.
Nine coins.
No!
At least we can buy another key.
Okay, thank God.
I think I thought I just messed it up.
I really did.
Playing card.
I could also buy a bunch of these, I guess, if I want to.
I'll take this and two of these.
Oh, wait, I can only buy one of them.
Right.
Okay, let's go.
It's gonna be good.
Wait, a two?
What is that?
Two, two, two... Oh, wait, spawn's piss item?
I have no idea why I wrote that.
I don't know what that means.
I'm gonna try.
Hey, at least I got my keys back.
Where did I?
Did I get something?
Ah, let me check all the rooms.
I did write spawn piss item.
Like the lemon one.
Maybe something spawned somewhere on the floor.
Maybe it's in the secret room.
No?
Nothing here.
Yeah, I have no idea.
No clue.
Weird.
Maybe it heals me or something, you know?
Maybe I've never been able to see it because it just heals me and I've had full HP or something.
That could be a thing.
Come over here, sir.
I'm totally gonna cheese-configurate the other guy.
Here we go.
You ready?
Let's get into a There we go.
Almost, almost.
Stay away from me.
Okay, some rain, some damage.
Why not?
The question is, should I be demon-ing?
Or should I be saving for Angel?
I think I'm gonna save for Angel, guys.
That's right.
I'm going full Angel.
I've started to see the light, you know, when it comes to Angels.
I need all the health I can get.
I can't be sacrificing that stuff for items.
That's my opinion on that.
I do good damage.
Would love a little bit more shot speed, though.
ROID RAGE.
More range.
Oh, that's two out of three on Spun.
I don't remember what Spun does.
But I assume it's good, you know?
Oh, I just lost a fly!
Or Wisp, I mean.
Speaking of, I should be using it every time it's full.
I forgot to read what I just got.
Damn.
I have no clue.
No idea what I just got.
Wait, I have a spoon.
Oh, wait, is that...
Is that an Epikak?
Do we have an Epikak on us?
Look at that!
There's an Epikak, there's a fly, and some kind of... Wait, what is that?
Are those egg stocks?
Uterus or something.
You know what I mean.
I just lost another Wisp.
Down here.
Whoa!
Let's go here.
Use diaper.
He has the Gator's Catol effect.
I mean, okay.
I don't have a trinket anyway, so I'll take it.
Wait, my shots are bouncing all over.
I have some kind of bounce item.
Nice.
I think we should do the boss now.
Yeah.
Mega fatty.
Trying to suck me in.
I say no to that.
Oh, he was fast.
How did I get hit?
Insanity.
Sometimes he jumps with the speed of light.
Even more range.
Calm down with the range.
No angel, unfortunately.
Very unfortunate.
Ah.
Next time, though.
Next floor.
Can't get that.
Man, I lost the whole heart.
Minimo speed and range up.
Okay, got it.
So much range.
I have so much.
My shots are bouncing all over.
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
So wait, if I use my Lamegaton right now, I think I'm gonna consume one, two, three, four of my red hearts, right?
Let me see.
Yep.
Okay.
Something about super complex.
I got a super complex.
Oh no, that's the concave thingy.
Damn.
I didn't get to read it in time.
Good.
Okay.
I lost some damage, though.
I must have lost one of my good wisps here, unfortunately.
Fight club.
I'm down.
Oh wait, this effect removes their projectiles.
Super duplex.
I
got...
Oh no!
My goddamn wisps.
Yeah, my shots are slow now, too.
Ooh, I don't know if that was worth it.
May not have been.
Okay, time for the shot.
We got 15 coins, man.
Jumper cables or... Oh, I'm actually drawn to the coupon.
Yeah, I have to take this.
This is just so good.
Amazing!
Oh, we can also use our red hearts on that one.
Interesting.
So we can choose.
Very cool.
And this one is the one that gives a bunch of cards, I think.
Not bad.
Time to leave.
Except I think I see a secret room location.
I'm gonna check all the rooms first, though.
I think this could be it.
Hell yeah!
Well, didn't really mean for that to happen, but okay.
Oh man, we're so low HP.
It may be over.
This is so bad right now.
Dude, not having any red hearts is just torture.
It really is.
It's like the bane of my existence, you know?
It's my ultimate weakness.
Okay, let's see if we can get an angel.
We need it bad.
And we need to make more wisps, but I don't want to use my red hearts on it.
I only want to use charge.
No, no, no, no!
I hate that!
Of course, it's got to be one of those enemies, you know?
Get in here.
Uh, what?
Oh, dude, dude, watch this!
We stack them!
I'm actually a mega IQ man.
Holy shit.
Screw.
Why not?
Uh, don't really want the rest.
I'm good.
I lost another wisp there.
This is bad.
Okay.
Black candle, curse immunity, and evil option.
Nice.
So that means angel for me right now.
Why do I always expect these guys to blow up?
We have a coupon ready.
No shop inside yet.
Dude, it's over.
Without any red hearts, I just can't play.
We have to go for this.
Angel, take me.
Just make a bunch of wisps right now, honestly.
Fucking hell.
Holy...
That's like the worst item in the game right here.
And no angel.
Like, are you actually for real?
I'm not gonna be the one to, you know, blame my losses on RNG.
But I lost because of RNG!
Sorry.
I'm okay.
It's fine.
Oh, nice.
Look at this.
We have this effect now.
Where's the shop, though?
Oh, one hit and I'm dead.
Come on.
Health uphill.
That's huge.
Okay, that's fine.
We had too much range anyway.
Also, we're flying.
What did I get?
I got something that made me fly.
One of my wisps is providing flight right now.
I like it.
Nine volt, quicker charge?
All right.
What about a store?
I got 26 bucks, man.
Burning a hole in my pockets.
Oh, I'm so scared.
We're playing this so safe right now.
We got a red bastard.
We got a fat bastard here.
Let's not get hit by this fly.
Dagas!
Hey, that's actually pretty good.
Just give me that heart now, honestly.
We already have curse immunity.
I think we still have the candle.
Oh my god, how did I dodge that?
Insanity.
Still no shop.
What?
I've mined giant spiders and flies.
Okay, whatever.
Path was questionable there.
What the hell is the kind of saw blade?
That's a new one.
Okay, you ready?
Here we go.
SMB super fan.
Super meat boy.
A lot of ranged damage too.
Ooh, that's nice.
That's a great freaking item.
I must have unlocked that recently because I've never seen that.
Finally the shop.
No, it's a fake shop.
I swear to god, RNG is fucking me.
I mean, I'm getting a lot of money here, but can't really spend it on anything.
A wasted coupon as well.
This whole floor has been a giant waste for the coupon.
I think I may see a secret though.
Hold on.
Possibly.
Let me check from this side.
Ah, I don't want to go in there, so let's just...
Damn.
Okay, maybe down here.
Nope.
Then I would say maybe here.
Let me check the other sides.
Otherwise, I'm going to regret it again.
Yeah, this one could be it.
Yes, sir.
Batteries.
Kind of want to take it, but I'm going to use this once.
Then I'm going to take this, use it again.
Mom's lipstick.
I didn't see what the other one was I got.
I was too excited.
Oh wait, we killed the boss already.
Ah, okay, well.
Let me think, do I want this?
Gain additional scent each time you pick up a coin?
Nah, I got so much already.
Go down.
Oh, we're already on the mom's day.
Holy shit, look at that map.
What the fuck?
We must have gotten some kind of map.
Oh yeah, we have a map.
That explains it.
Well, time to do some clearing.
Surely we will get through this without losing all of our HP, right?
Surely.
It doesn't reveal the stores though, or...
Wait, are there even stores here?
Yeah, there are.
I'm so scared of spiky chests right now.
I don't think I'm going to go in there, actually.
Bro, what?
How annoying are these guys?
Let's go here.
Fuck these skeletons.
They are the most dangerous ones.
A missing page.
5% chance to deal 80 damage to the room when taking damage.
Necromonic on black hearts.
And drive if you also do this increased damage.
I think my current one is better, honestly.
Yeah.
But I will pick it up just to get the necromancer thingy.
There we go.
Okay,
it's not too shabby.
Obsessed fan.
Follows my every move.
I'm familiar, right?
That's what that is.
Kind of want to blow this up here, actually.
Damn.
Enemies like this scare me right now, because they can easily take away my wisps if I'm not careful.
It's a good thing I have a lot of range.
Ooh, what's happening?
They were invisible or what?
What the hell just happened?
Fine.
I need to keep finding hearts here.
Blue hearts.
Shit.
Chain reaction.
Nice.
Stigmata.
Damage in HP up.
Ow.
So HP up doesn't work.
It's only the damage part that worked there.
I see.
Let's explore the bottom part first.
You can't reach me.
Also, I have spectral tears, it seems.
Matt, playing this character, you really need to understand what the items do, just based on the name.
To get full use out of it, you know?
There we go.
Okay, let me just have a peek in here.
Nice!
Good thing I did.
Yeah, not happening, bro.
Wait, a McDonald's membership card?
Oh, oh wait, I thought this was the one that gave me like a million bucks.
Too bad.
Okay.
Whoop.
Dude!
I think it just took away one of my Wisps.
Oh, there's another treasure room here.
Oh, because it's a big map.
You know what that means, right?
That means we probably have two shops as well, which is great for me.
That's huge that I just found that.
X-ray vision reveals an open secret room entrances.
Not bad.
That's very convenient.
Although a little late in the run, but you know, still.
Not too bad.
Fruitcake.
More random rainbow effects.
What the hell was that shot?
The world.
I mean, that's kind of useless here, I guess, but fuck the world.
Nope.
Only one shop.
At least we know where it is now.
Exciting.
I'm gonna beeline there immediately so I can use my coupon and possibly use it twice.
I'm not gonna open that chest.
The fastest way is through the secret room.
Kill him.
Good.
Another world?
That's funny.
Oh, looks like we got the...
No, never mind.
It was just a random effect.
Okay, shop time.
Okay, we can buy things.
Nice.
Definitely taking that.
I forgot to use my thing that could make things free, but you know what?
Hold on.
I'm starting to think, maybe it's better to save that for a potential angel.
But wait, those are free anyway.
That's only good if you're doing demons.
What's down here?
Mom's toenail?
Oh, that's horrible.
Horrible.
Familiar that occasionally...
Okay, that's pretty good.
I like that one.
Let's...
Ah, that's the toenail, of course.
Uh, wait, maybe I'll come back.
I think I'll buy this one.
I'll take that one.
We're gonna go back down.
See if we can make it free.
Ah!
Fine.
What about this one?
Puberty.
I'm gonna buy this card.
Yeah.
The tower.
Nah, that's not good.
What else do I need to do here?
I think I'm just gonna go to the boss.
I could also spend my hearts on rerolling right now.
You know what, I could also just buy it.
I have 32 gold.
It's not the worst idea.
I'm just gonna buy it.
I'm also thinking, maybe you don't need the coupon anymore.
Because I'm not gonna be doing devils anyway.
And I think from here on out, we're not gonna see shops.
Because we're gonna go into the uterus and all that.
So perhaps we just actually take the head.
Yeah.
I like it.
Could even donate some money.
Should I donate some money?
Yeah.
Full donation.
That way, if we lose this run, at least it's not all over, you know?
We still got something done.
Whoa!
Look at that one!
Ultimate bounce.
Oh, sick!
Do I want to keep that, though, is the question.
I'm gonna keep it for the boss.
But we have to remember, we're doing mom now.
So...
Actually, I'm gonna take the reveal the map.
No, no, no.
The map will be revealed by my x-ray glasses anyway.
Taking the strength.
These things we need to destroy.
Okay, too bad.
We have split shot right now.
For whatever reason.
Left hand replaces all chests that spawn with red chests.
No.
Like, that item is just incredibly mid.
And in fact, it's low.
It's like one out of ten.
I think sprinkler is even better.
A bomb for me.
I shall blow this up.
Another sun?
What's going on here?
I mean...
No, we don't need to use it.
I think I just lost a wisp.
No, I lost another one!
No!
Also, I forgot to use it.
Speak enough wisps.
Come on, please.
What's going on?
Loosing wisps left and right here.
Okay, uh...
I guess my plan is to keep going down, but we're not going to enter yet simply because we can't go back.
I'm not intending to go home, actually.
I want to either go to heaven or hell, and then kill the bosses there.
Wait, what was that?
Oh, it was bomb, okay.
Pull clear.
Zooming.
Magnetic tears.
What?
What do you mean?
Ah, wait.
Ooh!
Yo, this is kind of huge!
The question, though, is there like an upper limit?
Oh, wait, it's not charging my legemiton.
Nah, okay.
Whatever.
I'm actually gonna do this.
Okay.
Ooh!
Wait, why is that not charging my legemiton?
Okay, there we go.
It's charging my active first, it seems.
Mutant spider.
Quatch.
That's nice.
Very good.
Maybe we can hold on to the wisps now.
A little better.
Okay, I'm done.
Let's go.
There's nothing else I wanted in the shop.
One more bomb here.
Nothing in those skulls.
War, and then it's gonna be mom.
Jesus Christ.
The hell?
Uh, no, not the bandages!
I mean, I guess it's gonna help me absorb shots so my wisps don't take damage.
That's something.
Mom!
Oh, she's going crazy.
The hell is that?
Oh, sick!
Love shot eyes, belong her head!
I forgot what these things do.
Good night, mom.
Angels, finally.
Okay, you know what?
Let's go, uh...
We're gonna go Polaroid, I think.
Just to change it up a bit.
Oh, this one is so good!
That's one of the best ones.
We're gonna blow him up.
I need more tears.
Wiggle worm?
I mean, okay, I think that's kind of cool right now.
I dig it.
I do indeed.
Let's go.
The best part about this item is that I can now enter places like...
What do you call it?
Frickin' curse rooms without taking any damage and stuff.
Although, I'm actually kind of cursed right now, so that sucks.
Maybe we can get that fixed.
Wait, what does that actually do?
I'm drowsy.
Why can't I see it?
Oh, it slows everything for the room.
Maybe that's actually good for me.
But...
Yeah, I don't know.
Hold on, what's this?
Sick!
Very nice.
I'm taking this.
Yo, look at that effect!
Oh, that's kind of dope.
Wiggle worm?
Here we go.
Little Steven?
Oh, cracked key!
Wait, opens the door to a red room and used next to a valid wall.
Wait, why is that here?
Dude, I'm gonna be scanning every wall.
We're gonna...
There it is, baby!
Cracked key, is what he said.
No, I just lost.
I lost something on that.
It's fine.
I lost a very nice wisp, I think.
It is what it is.
Man, I can't stand not having a minimap right now.
Is that guy carrying something?
What happened?
Oh, it's nice.
Oh, we're definitely getting high in here.
What's that?
Shot speed down.
Oh, wait, I have to redo this room now.
I'm losing all my wisps for no reason right now.
I'm still flying.
I mean, I can't even use this money.
Compound fracture bone cheers.
Is that good?
That was kind of close.
Worms, yeah.
I have no idea how it's going right now, honestly.
Everything's a little bit chaotic.
I think it may be okay.
You know what, let's stick to the framework of sticking to one side right now.
We're going to stick to the right.
Our character's right.
So, yeah, we went through there, there's nothing.
So here now...
Use minimash speed and range up.
What's that?
What did I just get?
Chance of taking damage to destroy the trinket and spot an item from the current...
I mean...
Okay, you know what?
I'm actually excited about that.
I am.
What if we get a sick item, right?
This guy wants hearts.
Wait, I wonder.
Oh, what?
I thought we could give him from a pool of 30.
Come on, man.
Maybe this one?
No.
What?
I feel scammed.
Whatever.
What's happening?
I lost a wisp.
I think, and something else.
I can't fly anymore!
Oh, no.
I lost my ability to fly.
Wow.
If only these were blue hearts.
Am I ready to go?
I'm ready.
Skollex.
Drowd!
Looks like I lost my multi-shot.
Oh my god.
What was that?
Are you serious?
Oh, he was shooting bombs.
Okay, we got Angel.
We charge this one bar of Isaac's active each time he... Ah, that's terrible.
I don't want that item.
Gimme Blues.
Nice!
Okay, well that's good.
I'm gonna blow him up.
No!
How did I get hit by that?
Pull yourself together, man.
What?
Dude!
Bullshit!
He's like, cardinal directions?
Okay, now I'm finally dodging diagonally and then he does diagonal.
Like, there's no way to know which one he's gonna do.
I think I'm just gonna go down.
Because I don't even want to bother with this map when I don't have the minimap for it.
It's absolute torture for me.
Okay, let's go down here.
Wait, oh yeah, I can't fly anymore, right?
I keep thinking I can fly.
Wait, I have holy water.
Secrets!
Oh, that's a good one, guys!
That's a really good one.
A chance of finding Devil Rooms.
Oh, that's all this good stuff here.
Oh, hell yeah.
Wow.
Wowers.
Wowcees.
Also, we can totally use the Megaton, but I have to save it.
Okay, go here.
I also lost my ability to do spectral chairs, it seems, in the process here.
Oh, god.
Toy!
Scary as room.
Wait, why are they all, like, petrified at the start?
Must be a random item I have.
Oh, no, it was the random tear effects, I think.
Yo, whatever that effect was, give me more of that.
Ah, but I can't fly.
Panic equals power?
Maybe that's, like, how low HP I have.
Maybe even more low HP and more panic?
Would make sense to me.
Oh, didn't mean to do that.
But I guess I have to, because I can't fly anyway.
Hey, what are we gonna get?
I'm gonna bring these together.
I'm smart.
Is that strength?
Okay, nice.
Not too shabby.
Nice room.
Here's a boss.
Could do that, but not yet.
Man, I gotta get used to no flying.
Bring him together.
And this guy, come on.
Good enough.
What's that?
Oh, this one.
We don't need bombs.
Well, we kind of do, actually.
I'll trade some keys for bombs.
Just a couple.
Get in there and get that.
Guess we're going north.
Oh.
Holy shit.
Wait, do I have a sci-fi effect on me?
I'm not sure, actually.
Nah, we just lost a fly, I think.
Oh, no.
Another step.
Nice.
Oh, that was actually kinda sick.
The way I handled that was beautiful.
Key bomb, he wants your keys.
Do we let him take them?
I think it's okay.
Get him.
Let's go here.
Stutter step, stutter step.
Solid.
Dude, I'm spawning flies left and right.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh!
Where are you?
How do I get in there?
Answer, I don't.
Dude, come on.
Nice.
Oh, man.
Another key.
I gotta say, man, my followers are actually doing a lot of work.
Because they're absorbing shots that would have hit my wisps otherwise.
Halo of flies.
Projectile protection, that sounds nice.
And we're kinda done here now.
Time for boss.
One thing I'll say, though.
I think before we go in there...
We may spawn a bunch of items.
Actually, go in here.
The whole point of this is to be able to go in here, right?
The mantle, I mean.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
Ghost pepper, flame tears.
Splash, that's another one?
Oh, look at that!
We can shoot two of them.
Yada, buddy.
Robo baby.
Pop!
Eyeball tears.
Yo, listen.
Damage resistance.
Nice.
Restock.
Uh, wait, really?
Ah, we don't have a store here.
PhD, better... okay, that's fine for now.
Let's go.
Can we kill this guy over here?
Why am I... tears so slow?
I mean, it's working.
We got her.
We got her, ladies and gentlemen.
Uh, the question is...
No, we gotta go up.
It's time to go up.
Unfortunately, no angel and no nothing.
Let's go.
Nice.
We got secret here.
Who's this fool?
Oh, wait, I can't.
Damn.
Dude, I want a better active.
Crazy that I haven't found something better at this point, right?
I mean, I don't need your money, man.
That's so huge.
I love finding blue hearts, man.
I don't know what kind of effect I have going right now, but I like it.
E.
coli.
Love me some E.
Another secret discovered.
Wait, did I get something there?
One lock?
Okay.
Ah, it had to happen at some point.
Not a big deal, though.
Again?
You're kidding me.
Go west.
Go worst.
Another pill?
Ah, I don't want less shot speed.
No, thanks.
Dude, I'm gonna smack Isaac.
Like, it's not even gonna be close.
I've got that guy's number.
I'm an actual expert at that boss.
Although, I will say it's been a while since I did it.
But still.
Damn!
Wait, that's my last bomb!
Oh, shit!
How am I running out of bombs?
That's crazy.
Mom's perfume?
I forgot another heart there.
I just lost a fly.
What even is this?
There's so much shit on my screen!
No idea what's happening.
Oh, yeah.
Butt bombs!
Hey, I got some bombs!
No, I didn't get some bombs.
It lied.
It said plus five bombs, I didn't get it.
Because it's only passives.
Dude, those inanimate objects are crazy.
Okay, battery.
Stay at max range!
I would like homing tears.
That would be nice.
Just so I can stay at max range, you know, and plink away.
I'm stuck, I'm stuck!
Oh, yo, yo, yo, yo!
Man!
Ares, ramming speed.
Wait, what?
Oh, I don't get the effect on that.
It's just the passive.
Unfortunate.
I love the mantle.
Wait, okay, there we go.
What's this?
Size of Isis farts is increased?
No.
No, I don't want that.
Dude, hit him!
Thank you.
This is huge!
We got full HP!
Well, almost full.
Full HP.
Oh god, this guy's protected as hell!
This is a crazy room.
Wow.
Bogobombs, one plus one, boom.
Isaac!
Papa fly.
Oh my god, I'm losing all my wisps.
How am I supposed to avoid that with these wisps?
Like, I have too much of a hitbox.
Like, legitimately, fighting Isaac with all these wisps is almost impossible.
You're gonna get hit.
Hitbox too large, man.
Oh nice, it looks like we got some kind of bomb effect on my tears.
That's gonna be big.
Oh, it was just temporary, I think.
Like, you see that?
I was out of the way, and yet he hit my wisp with it.
Oh wait, he's shooting at me right now.
But wait, this is not the end though, why can't I continue?
Why is there not a way to fucking jump down?
Or up, I mean.
No idea.
I feel like there usually is like a way to con...
Oh, nevermind, there is.
There it is.
I was like, okay, there we go, that's the end.
I forgot about this.
And now, yeah, the key has been fit in.
Spider Bites, Tooth and Nail.
Dacryfetchy.
D4.
Oh, you know what actually?
Dude, I'm feeling the D4.
I'm doing it.
Ooh, exciting.
Mr. Dolly.
Anemic.
Mom's Heels.
Bobby Bomb.
Dead Eye.
Glitter Bombs.
Matchbook.
Mom's Ring.
Spider Mod!
Latch Key.
Forever Alone.
Blue Map.
Tarot Cloth.
Experimental Treatments.
The Polaroid.
Pechel Candle.
That's a stacking, tears bonus for each room cleared.
Okay, okay.
Cursed Eye.
Jesus Juice.
Dude, I can do it again.
If I want to.
But I don't want to, I think.
Wait, look at this one!
We're shooting like little...
Okay, maybe that's exciting.
Not Gobby's head again!
Kidding me?
Maybe I'll reroll everything again.
We'll see how it goes.
Oh, I got Jim.
Nice.
What's that?
Halo of Flies?
Cool.
This run is weird now.
I don't have a lot of range, though.
Oh!
Wait, what happened?
Wait, do I have that item that makes me teleport when I get hit while charging?
Which one is that?
Oh!
It's that one!
Cursed Eye!
Makes sense.
I feel a little bit like...
Jeremiah.
No, it's Hazel.
Jim, Jim, Jim.
Let me in.
What the hell is this?
I've got money!
I've got plenty of money.
This is like my dream.
Oh, what's that?
Forever Gamble.
We're gambling forever.
Gambling forever.
I can't see my screen.
What was that?
Tell me it's like a manual way to do this.
Reveals the map and drops a card.
Ruin a soul heart.
Increase the chance of a planet.
Sure.
Two of diamonds.
Wait, that's money, isn't it?
Show me.
Yeah?
We have money for days, guys.
More luck.
I'll take it.
How's this?
Speed...
Oh, I'm really slow now.
I'm a fat fuck.
Look at this.
Oh, no.
This is...
Oh, wait, is that...
Oh, that's the D4, right.
Ah, I guess I can...
Let me just keep gambling.
Oh, nice.
That's also good for me.
Pick those up.
Please don't explode.
Also, I'm gonna use this now.
Where's the diamond card there?
92 coins now.
Is that a toilet roll I spy?
Wait, I didn't mean to do that.
What is this thing?
Duct tape.
Familiars will stick in their relative positions.
Nah, I don't like that.
Steven...
What did I just get?
Oh, tinted rocks and rocks covering crawl spaces will occasionally gleam.
I'm just gonna keep gambling until it breaks.
I can't see.
Remove the thing.
12 troll bombs.
I guess we have an effect that doubles the effect of cards.
We're gonna get full HP from this, by the way.
Oh, friendship necklace.
Familiars orbit around Icy.
I mean, they already do, kinda.
So it's confusing.
It's just faster, maybe.
What's that?
Monkey paw spawns a black heart when...
Let me read it.
When Icy gets reduced to half a heart.
This drink is consumed?
No.
We're never gonna get to half a heart, because we don't have any hearts.
We only have blue hearts.
Ooh, this is exciting.
Aowas.
Ooh, Aowas!
Love me some Aowas.
I'll be back.
I'm gonna Aowas right here on this piece of paper.
That's some kind of baby.
Best friend.
Places a decoy that draws enemies to it and explodes.
You know what?
Why not?
I'll take it.
God, there's too much shit on the floor.
You know what?
Let's do...
See if we can't draw all the items away.
Go over there.
Wait, why are they moving randomly?
I'm not sure what's happening with the items movement here.
Another heart, nice.
What is that?
Broken Onk.
22% chance to revive as...
Honestly?
Could be pretty cool to have.
Oh no, it broke finally.
Okay, well there it is.
Reroll all item pedestals in the current room.
Wait, hold on.
This may actually work on these.
But I'm not gonna do it yet.
These are item pedestals.
Oh, actually, I need to...
No, I need bombs.
Crazy that I haven't gotten more bombs from this, right?
It's drowsy.
It's actually not a bad pill to have.
Oh, portable slots.
Yeah.
Check it out, we're gonna do this.
Like that, right?
And then we do this.
Are you ready?
Let's go out here and do it here.
No, no, go in here.
No, go out here.
No, go, go down here.
This is a nice, empty room.
HEABOW Maximumei Holy shi-i-i-i-i-it...
bro.
Let's see what we get.
Pretty fly.
Minus one range... I hate it.
Pu-birdy.
I love it.
Another health up?
I mean, sure.
Why not?
Take the money, we can gamble even more.
Here we go.
Unidentified.
Lock up, range down.
You know what, I'm not...
Okay, that actually kind of sucks.
I have no range right now.
That's real bad.
It's fine though.
I have no money left.
More minus range?
What's up with that?
Okay, per throw time.
Let's go see if this works.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I actually maybe want to keep the d4.
Switch these out like that.
Yeah, that's good.
Here we go.
You ready?
Yeah, it works!
Okay, what do we get?
One up.
Ranch one.
Oh!
Hey, that's awesome!
Not bad.
Raw liver?
Oh, that's bad for me.
That's bad.
I also have death and strength.
Drowsy.
Oh, health up, nice.
Not that I need that right now.
Oh, we have more money here too.
Range... Oh, that's good!
We like range.
Bad trip is bad.
Give me that one.
I'll take this.
What was the green one?
Bob's bladder?
Placing a... No, I don't want the... Yeah, that's fine.
We have the tower.
No, give me this back.
I think we're done in here.
What do I want to keep?
Maybe strength.
Yeah, death is not that great.
I think we're done here.
I don't need the rest of these pills.
Maybe, honestly, maybe Drowsy is even better than strength.
Drowsy is kind of crazy, actually.
Let's go to the secret room.
Oh, we also got to use the Megaton quite a bit.
Good damage.
We got some good damage here.
Spider... That's going to make us Spider Baby.
What does that do?
Let's see.
Let's pay attention.
I think we spawned a spider.
Or something.
Also, I'm kind of nervous about running around with the D4 in my hand.
What if I accidentally space bar?
I kind of want to go back and change it out.
Shit, we got Embrace the Chaos.
That's bad.
Do I even have any actives?
I may not actually have any actives.
Oh, well.
It is what it is.
If I accidentally hit space bar, it's just going to get more interesting.
It's going to get really interesting if that happens.
What the hell is that?
Black Hole.
Throws a black hole that pulls in and damages enemies.
While active, it also pulls in pickup items and destroys nearby obstacles.
That's fucking awesome.
Well, that's what I wanted.
I wanted to exchange my active, and there I go.
Let me try.
Oh, so it does it where I stand.
I see.
Okay.
The map is bothering me.
Gimme.
Did I just lose my last wisp?
God damn.
Oh no, I lost like a really great effect on my attack.
I see how much damage I have now.
If I can hit anything.
It's decent, I guess, but it's nothing like I had before.
We're going to get Beelzebub, whatever that is.
There's a fire exact here to spawn a blue spider increases with luck.
We have seven luck, though.
That's good.
We're flying now.
I love that.
Oh, that's a bomb.
It hurts.
Taking damage fires a ring of 10 large tears and grants a stacking tears stat bonus for the current room.
These ring tears leave bloody.
Is that a trinket?
Oh, no, it's not.
Oh shit.
Well, obviously you take that then.
Yeah, my new attack is not as good as the one I had before.
What the hell was that?
Gimme this.
What is that?
Midas touch!
Golden touch?
Petrify and turns enemies to gold on touch.
Heals contact damage that increases with coin count.
Gilded enemies drop coins when... Whoa!
Chance for spawn poops to be golden.
All right, that sounds very interesting.
Let's go to that secret room.
Oh!
Oh, right.
This is a thing.
Oh, well.
Dude, that's gonna hurt.
I almost want to reroll all my shit just because I have the cursed eye, guys.
Like, that can really fuck me later.
This is actually bad.
Dude, I'm doing it.
I'm doing it.
Here we go.
You ready?
Do this.
Fuck it!
Conjoined!
We're still flying, it seems.
Wait, are we actually?
Hold on, what's happening?
No, it's my follower.
Okay, what am I shooting then?
Wait, I have no idea what's happening.
Let's see here.
Dessert.
The inner eye.
Oh, we don't have the other eye, I don't think, hopefully.
Rotten baby.
Torn photo.
Holy light!
Chance to fire holy tears to summon a damaging beam of light.
Okay.
And... Perisitor, chance to fire exact tears first.
No!
Shit, we still have it, guys.
We're gonna clear a bit and then use it again.
Shit, oh no, I don't want this pill, actually.
Give me this.
Okay, I need some battery.
Wait, I think I have batteries somewhere lying around.
Did we have, like, a whole room full of batteries?
Up here.
There's like a million batteries in here.
Oh, wait a minute!
Did we get something that makes pills good?
No, it doesn't look like it.
No.
What was this card?
Troll bombs.
Eh.
Shit.
Alright, well... Whatever.
Let's just keep exploring.
Oh no, maybe the current build is crazy.
I gotta see it in combat.
Oh, give me this.
I need to see this thing in effect, you know?
Yeah, so I don't have any idea what's happening, but things are dying, so thumbs up.
Did that chest just disappear?
You saw that, right?
That chest just disappeared.
Loki's horns, chance to fire tears in all four cards.
I like it.
Oh wait, the secret was here.
I have a very slow charge, though, which is bad.
Dude, the way tears are bouncing around the room is kinda nuts.
Wait, I wonder, hold on, if I sit in a corner like this.
Dude, I can sit here and just spam!
Maybe it's fine.
Like, this is actually... Like, look at this.
I'm gonna go over here.
Okay, I think we got a winner.
The chest disappeared again.
Dude, I don't want to say the game is bugged.
You saw that, right?
It disappeared again.
Something's going on that I don't understand, okay?
I'm not saying it's bugged, something's just happening that I don't understand, that's all.
Thank you.
Okay, we got a couple rooms left to explore.
Go in the corner.
This is sick.
Charge up.
I mean, not that... Gimpy!
That's a good one.
We like Gimpy.
Dead tooth, toxic breath.
I think I'm ready to throw away my d4, dude.
I think I can live with a cursed eye.
I'm not even kidding.
We're gonna go take the black hole.
Like, this is crazy.
Gimpy.
Uh, boss time.
I could also make a bunch of items.
Should I make some?
Yeah, why not?
Car battery.
Wait, why am I getting two at once?
I don't know why I'm getting so much.
I probably have, like, some kind of item that does that.
What's happening?!
Oh, shit!
I got hit!
Okay, we try again.
Go in the corner and just sit there.
This is a problem with the cursed eye, man.
Stop picking that pill up!
Okay, let's actually use that pill this time.
We're also gonna use a black hole, because I forgot to do that last time.
Here we go.
Black hole for you.
Why is it over there?!
Oh, he's shooting towards the black hole or...?
Dude, I can't see his projectiles.
We have to re-roll again, guys.
I can't play like this.
We're re-rolling again.
It's impossible.
Wish me luck.
We have a flashlight now.
Guys, I'm not even gonna look at my items.
I'm just gonna say whatever.
Huh?
Okay, whatever this is, it's good.
I don't know what's happening.
We're gonna try this one now.
Let's get in there and have some fun.
Yeah, you like that, bitch?
Look at my red stuff.
Dude, the game is lagging.
No idea what's happening.
No idea.
We're gonna jump down.
We're jumping down, baby.
I like the current setup.
The current setup has been approved.
Fuck yeah.
Wait, things have changed.
Wait, why are things different now?
Fragment card.
What?
Why are my attacks so weird now?
What's that?
Hey, nice.
I mean, I'm still doing good damage.
There's no denying that.
Oh, wait, he took a heart from me.
Okay.
Oh, no, I want that.
Got a pill here as well.
Crazy that I don't have flying.
He stole my heart, this bastard.
Justice.
Got a black heart.
The first black heart I've seen.
I guess I found some flies.
Okay, so this is the one with a million bosses.
I don't know if I like my build anymore, man.
It was good when I was back in the other place.
Why is it suddenly weird and different?
I didn't do anything.
I feel cheated.
Meat.
Oh, wait a minute.
I forgot about the door.
I shouldn't have jumped down yet.
Oh, shit.
Damn.
It is what it is.
We take those casualties.
Something hurts.
Uh, lock.
Yeah, I'll take it.
Honestly, I don't even remember what's down that door anyway.
Oh, look at this!
The first intended rock!
Okay, okay.
Can I want to find another D4?
I'm not liking my current setup.
I'm not... I'm not even flying.
Like, what is that?
In this economy, I'm not even flying?
That's like the minimum.
Looks like I have the item that automatically heals after a while.
Placenta.
I mean, my damage is not that bad, but it's kind of bad.
I think the boss is... Wait, where is the boss?
Ah, here.
The good news is, I don't think we have cursed eye anymore.
And I'm not even gonna check.
I'm gonna let it be a surprise.
If we get teleported, we get teleported.
So be it.
The fuck?
Oh, I thought that was a portal to downstairs.
Let's go deal with the boss.
Oh!
What's that?
Justice.
I just lost a wisp.
Feels bad, yo.
Okay, we got boss here.
Wish me luck.
It's a gate.
No!
I will not be able to hold on to these wisps.
Angry fly.
Wait, my Beelzebub, man.
I had Beelzebub.
Now I don't.
Feels real bad.
But I probably have something else.
Wait, my damage is good as long as I can hit with it, right?
I have a suspicion that my current build somehow relies on the floor I'm on.
Like every floor I get a new tear effect or something.
How else can you explain what happened, right?
It stole my heart, that asshole.
I needed that heart.
Gimme, you're not taking that.
Like, look at that damage.
That damage is top notch.
Top notch damage.
That's a very good item.
That just boosted my damage by a gazillion.
Wow.
We're shooting black shots now as well.
I love it.
Oh, I will fly again somehow.
Nice.
Oh, shit.
Excuse me.
Do you mind if I, you know, get up there, maybe?
Fuck!
Impossible.
Don't take him.
Don't take him good.
I need more tears.
You're not taking that.
Don't take that.
I got 13 bombs.
Let's do more bosses.
Mom!
It lifts.
It doesn't though.
Oh, you died fast.
You did, son.
Wait, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
This may actually be bad for me.
This may actually be bad.
But I'm going to take it because this run is complete chaos.
And I invite all the chaos into my life.
I have no idea why it looks like that.
I'll take it.
Looks awesome.
Looks like a winner.
Get blasted.
Holy shit.
The Bible.
I forgot, I keep forgetting to use my black hole as well.
Judgment.
Okay, don't take my heart.
Oh, wait, what?
This is not the guy.
Too fast for you.
Okay, we move on.
Dude, I don't, I don't know what's happening, but I love it.
I call this the blind way of playing the game.
You never look at your items.
You hold, you hold a hand in front of your eyes and you just accept what's on screen.
It's a lot of fun.
Holy.
I will say though, my charge speed is very slow.
I need more tears.
Get blasted, nerd.
And again, it's kind of a big blast that we're making with it, so maybe it's okay.
I feel
like that guy from Star Wars right now.
The guy who goes, unlimited power.
You know, that guy.
Okay, we got a couple of bosses up here that need a bit of spanking.
Yeah.
Oh, I didn't charge.
That's fine though.
We made it.
Weird
room.
Hey, the good news is I don't need to charge fully to shoot.
Stop shooting him.
Okay, so I'm gonna go right.
Loki.
He did.
Don't I already have a gimp?
Whatever.
That's another Loki.
Oh, you did.
Damn.
I was too fast for him.
Move on.
What's this room?
It honestly may be more DPS if I just do this.
I'm not sure.
Okay, here we go.
It's Isak.
This is round two.
See ya.
Bye-bye.
I'll take more speed.
Didn't I leave behind a card somewhere?
Did I actually do every boss except the actual boss?
That's kind of crazy.
No way, right?
More luck.
I mean, more chance on lock shots, whatever.
Oh, thanks.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
You ready?
Jupiter.
I'm a big fat bastard now.
And wait, we're gonna just use a bunch of these.
We got some items.
Okay.
I don't know what's happening.
I'm scared.
What is happening?
Why is my character on the side of the screen?
I can't see.
Oh, wait.
I have the thing that... Oh, I see.
I see now.
I understand.
We have a little thingy.
I don't know.
Dude, I don't know what's happening.
Wow.
Wait, he's dead already?
Dude, my game is lagging.
I need to go.
Okay, it's too sad.
The Megatron has appeared.
So I can find that now.
That's so nice.
Okay, guys.
Apparently, Bethany's pretty good.
Pretty good.
I like it.
Yep.
Not bad.
But we're not done.
We're gonna... Dude, let's randomize this.
We are going... No, wait.
I don't want to randomize in case I get a character I've already gotten a tainted version of.
So we're gonna do... Let me think.
Maybe... No, what is the character that I have the least sort of things on?
Judas, I guess.
But we already did that guy.
We can try Cain or Magdalene.
Or Isaac.
Wait.
Jacob.
Euless.
Kinda wanna... Dude, Eden.
Let's do Eden.
Let's try Eden.
I like it.
We're starting with a funny thing.
Scatter bombs and notched axe.
There's attack buttons to swing it.
And break rocks and damage enemies, but as limited users before.
Okay.
Uh, sure.
One red heart.
Sorry, excuse me.
Yeah, one red heart.
This is a bad item.
I don't like that.
Me no gusta.
Okay, that was nice, actually.
Uh, let's not use it now.
We have limited uses.
Dude, this could be a stepper.
We have a stepper room as well.
But the thing is, we have two blue right now, so that's bad.
If I accidentally lose that, then it could be good.
Uh, I'm gonna use this.
Why is it so heavy?
Okay.
Jesus.
Oh.
Good.
Now we focus on these guys.
Oh.
Oh my god, please stand still.
Wait, I forgot to take the item that dropped.
How?
Come on.
Man, it's always rough in the beginning, huh?
See what I got here.
Also, tinted rocks is something we really need to be looking for.
Typically because I have this axe.
Okay.
Five coins.
Ooh, man, I really wanna eat pills.
This is a cheap one.
That's really good, actually.
You know what we can do?
Check it out.
We're actually gonna go step.
Then I'm gonna come back here and grab this afterwards.
Yeah.
And then we still have a buffer.
This is the way.
Oh, this room is gonna be annoying.
Ah, it's fine.
Another heart is great.
You take half a heart, I think, by stepping on that.
We gotta pay attention.
Could actually be a full heart.
If it is, then we're kinda screwed.
I'm getting pretty good at the early stages.
Another red heart.
Damn.
Wait, another tre- Hold on.
We're double troubling.
Sure, I'll take this.
I think what happened there, the other spider jumped right at the moment the first one exploded.
So it didn't take damage from the explosion.
Okay, here we go.
No, it's a full one!
Shit.
Then we can't do it.
Well, I can do it once, I guess.
Only once.
Wait, what?
Why did I only take a half there?
Guys, I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna fucking trust my...
I don't understand this game.
I don't.
I don't get it.
It makes no sense.
First, I take a full heart of damage.
At least I thought I did.
Then I take a half heart when I was checking.
I'm like, okay, guess it is half a heart.
Then I do it again.
Full heart.
What?
Stupid.
No idea why it is like that.
I don't want to play with you anymore.
We're gonna take another character.
Let's do Samson.
Okay, I forgot what his actual like gimmick is.
Three red hearts.
I love to see that though.
Does he have any items or something?
Oh, what wasn't it?
This is the guy that when you take damage, then you deal more damage, I think.
That's actually what it is.
So actually, check this out.
I'm gonna do this.
0.5 damage.
I take this now.
Boom.
Not bad, eh?
Oh, I could have actually just done it in here.
That would have been smart.
That would have been the way to do it, right?
That would have been even better.
It's fine though.
I'm not angry.
Slowly but surely, I'm cleaning up.
I will never trust the step ever again.
Dude, this room only took me 12 years.
Okay, it's a decent item, I guess.
Could be worse.
Now, this is a good idea.
Check it out.
We're gonna get some damage out of that.
And it's for a good cause, you know?
Whoa!
Oh, I hate them.
I hate them.
There's nothing worse than being like excited for this and then you hate it.
But I think I'll take this one.
Yeah.
That one wasn't active.
That's damage up and speed down.
Contact damage can break rocks off of Black Heart.
Nah, I'm good.
Now we're a little bit in scary land.
We don't have any health at all.
At least we have this conjoined thing.
Unidentified.
Dude, I'm hearing a sound of running water.
Are you hearing it?
Oh, maybe it's not in the game.
Shit.
I was hoping for a bomb in there, at least, just to recuperate.
Oh, this guy's gonna fu- this guy's so damn difficult.
Never mind, he did.
Wait, how?
Wait, how did he die so fast?
What the fuck?
How did he just die that quick?
I have no idea.
This is a mystery.
This guy just fucking fell over and gave up.
100% demon and we don't- oh wait, I forgot to buy the- no, wait, that was last run.
Obviously, we forgot to buy the Blue Heart.
I guess I've erased the last run from my memory, because that was just not good.
Okay.
Oh shit.
Do I want I'm not gonna walk into the curse.
Wait, you didn't get stunned.
Come here, walk in that.
Yeah.
Nice.
Ooh, nice.
Oh, it's right here too.
I don't have a bomb.
Gotta find a bomb.
I think they actually sold the bomb up in the shop.
So I could go back for that first case.
Shit.
Holy shit, that was close, guys.
Almost lost my demon.
I kind of clutched that.
I'm not gonna lie, that was sick.
Damn, nothing.
Get petrified.
Dude, the petrification is actually kind of clutch.
Where's my water?
Oh, there it is.
Okay, so wait, hold on.
Petrifies and turns enemies to gold on touch.
Deals contact damage that increases with coin count.
Gilded enemies drop coins when killed.
Chance for spawn poops to be golden.
Okay.
So basically, the strategy is to have a buffer and then walk into enemies.
Turn them golden, destroy them to get more gold, and then the cycle continues.
I guess that's sort of the idea.
Oh,
dude, the holy water, man!
Okay, holy water, you need to carry me now.
Respawn, respawn.
There we go.
Gimme!
Yep, good, good, good, good.
Solid.
We're gonna make this guy jump on the holy water.
Shit.
I guess it was only when he was joined up with the other guy.
Cheese configuration!
No, it's too hard for a cheese right now.
We can't do it.
Hey!
Wait, angel?
Wait, why are we getting angels?
Is it the holy water?
Is that the oil?
I have no idea.
Sure, I'll take some damage.
I'm a little curious, though.
I'm a little unsure about this.
I need a bomb, man, so I can get to the secret room.
Dude, has this been, like, perfect gameplay so far?
This may actually be perfection territory.
Let's go check the shop for the bomb.
Could also go in here.
Yeah, why not?
There's my bomb.
It didn't sell a bomb, okay.
Uh, seven.
Nah, I don't want to spend my coins.
We're gonna go to that secret room.
I guess I can give him some keys.
Come on now, don't take too many.
Yeah, yeah.
Cause it's too... I mean, no.
Wait, what is the one I currently have?
Increase the chance of encountering the bible.
Win a devil room.
Oh!
No!
That's what did that.
Right.
Makes sense.
I like it, then.
Rosary bead is... Thumbs up!
Moving on.
Third floor.
We got a door.
That was bad with the...
Go!
Come onto my territory, noobs!
You want to get in here?
You want to get in on this?
Yeah!
I'm really focusing on not taking damage here!
Dude, did that guy just get stopped in his tracks right before he hit me?
That was like some divine intervention shit.
You saw that?
Okay, this guy wants bombs.
Absolutely not.
Oh, no, no, no, not this room!
Ah, no thanks.
I'll be back.
This boss is surely down here, anyway.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit!
Oh, god.
Oh, god!
We're fine.
I need a buffer, and I need it now!
This room is not great, either, but I'm gonna go through it.
I mean, a higher chance of finding the bible, right?
Means we can probably fly in there, maybe?
They call me the creep master!
The master of creeps.
Uh, do I?
Nah, nah, can't do it, chief.
Not yet.
I'm too ski- Walk into my office!
No, wait, how did I take damage?
What?
That was nothing there!
Whatever.
Apparently, my office is very unsuitable for myself.
It's a hostile work environment, clearly.
Go!
That was a bad- That was a bad-
Okay, we're safe.
Dude, this room is nuts!
Oh, I know what that effect was!
I walked into someone, they became gold!
All right, that's what it was.
So wait, that means if you walk into someone, and the gold effect happens, you don't take damage!
That's kind of nice!
That's really nice, actually.
Would have loved to go in here with a higher angel chance, but you know.
This, what it is.
These guys are not affected by the holy water.
They're flying, I guess.
You can't explain that.
Here, just for you.
I felt like doing it.
What do you want?
Four soul?
That's nice, that's actually a huge buffer for next floor.
So here's the deal, we're gonna wait with taking that.
Just in case I take damage while exploring, because I'm not done exploring.
This is the next level strats we got here.
North!
You know what, I just realized something.
You have like a little grace period when you enter a room before they start shooting.
Did you see that?
Not bad.
I'm actually gonna open this.
What do we got here?
Pisces, more tiers, higher tier size, knockback, yeah.
Solid.
Flat file.
Oh, that's actually pretty good as well.
But no, I'd rather keep my rosary.
Spider modulus!
We may have to...
Oh no, it's the re-roll!
I was gonna blow it up to get the spider mod.
No.
Okay, I know what we're doing.
Curse rule, save me.
Wish me luck.
There's better be some money in there.
Because I sure need it.
I don't think there's money in here.
There's money in here!
Ha ha ha!
And let's go back.
Two bombs, I could look for a secret.
But I'm not entirely sure where it could be, so...
Let's not gamble it.
Dude, let's gamble it.
It's right here.
Ha!
Oh shit, that's a bad bomb.
Bad bomb, bad boy!
I'm sorry.
We get two bombs out of it.
It's a good trade.
Oh, that was close.
I'm actually gonna take this.
Wait, what am I doing right now?
Oh yeah, shop.
Yeah, spider mud!
Yoink!
It is mine.
Dude, let's go crazy.
Pilk!
Nice!
I like that actually.
I needed more bombs.
And now we take the pajamas and we get the bejesus out of here.
Not this way.
I can walk through here.
No, I can't.
Yes, I can.
LOCKY PENNY!
I'm glad I went that way.
Okay, now we take this.
Go.
Solid floor.
Fourth floor, coming up.
It's the flooded caves and we have a curse of darkness.
But we have a huge buffer and we love it.
Ooh!
Uh, not yet.
We're gonna come back for that.
No forgetting spaghetti this time.
And if we do forget spaghetti, then no upsetting spaghetti.
There's someone else in here with me.
Step into my office!
Haha!
Dude, I may actually...
You know what, I'm gonna say it.
The holy water is kinda S tier.
Wait, six is bad I think.
Hold on.
Six, six, six.
We roll all items!
Yeah, I like my items, thank you.
My items are okay.
Also remove that.
Or I forget.
Okay.
Keep exploring.
Short fuse?
No thanks.
I especially love spider mod in situations like this.
Where I know how many shots I need to kill them, you know?
Boss?
Uh, let's do it!
While we have the buffer.
Mega fatty.
I'm gonna mega destroy him.
Wait, what?
Step into my office!
Why won't he do it?
There we go.
He's in there.
He's not liking it.
Good damage.
Toothpicks.
And we got this bad boy going on.
What is that again?
Eternal.
Ooh.
Allows angel rooms to appear even if a devil deal has been taken.
Real chance reduction is decreased?
I don't know what that means, actually.
Also, I heard something.
There's something in here.
What did I just pick up?
I picked up something behind this guy's butt.
I'm not sure what it is.
He stepped into my office.
Big mistake.
I'm stuck!
So is he.
I
was lucky.
And my damage is not that great, I will say.
Okay.
Absolutely amazing.
We're not done, though.
Not yet.
I want to find a holy mantle.
Now that would put a smile on my face like nothing else.
Oh!
I'm so bad.
I heard that.
You heard that?
I heard it.
Oh my god, oh my god, oh my god.
No problem.
I'm Neo.
How did I get hit?
Nice.
We gotta maintain that heart there.
Actually, if I pick up the other heart now, it's like...
Then we get a full heart, you know?
Nice.
No!
I fell for the oldest trick in the book again.
You know, it's not actually that sad to fall for the oldest trick.
Because it is the oldest.
Nobody remembers it, right?
So it's more effective.
Have you ever thought about that, huh?
Bet you haven't.
Four coins, that's despicable.
I could blow it up.
And get a coupon.
Because I need an active.
You know what?
I'm gonna do it.
Fuck it.
I've been saving so much money lately.
I think I can afford to do a little bit of...
You know...
That.
Come on, baby!
Damn!
Okay, well...
I'm gonna come back with some battery, maybe.
Probably not.
We don't have that many rooms left, I think.
I should go grab that eternal heart.
Yeah, let's do it before we lose, like...
The full blue heart and then also the eternal heart.
I guess it wouldn't matter, actually.
Because we're gonna get this anyway and then finish...
The floor, right?
You know, optimally, it would be best not to pick it up.
Because I could've...
Maybe gotten a full eternal heart.
No, nevermind, actually it's fine.
If we find another eternal heart now, it's gonna, you know, carry on to the next floor.
And it'll all work out.
Why you gotta give me this as soon as I find my actives, huh?
For Christ's sake.
I don't like that.
Oh, I'm going back to the shop, baby!
Battery achieved!
We really need some luck now.
Like, some good luck.
Luck!
Actually, here's what we're gonna do.
I have a perfect idea, check it out.
We're gonna take this right here.
We're gonna take this.
We make our own luck.
Boom.
What does this even do?
Clearing room spawns two rewards.
Only one reward can be taken.
Nice.
Okay, I think we're ready to move.
Actually, there is a corridor we missed.
You know I gotta go there.
Dude, I'm kinda considering going in the dice room and rerolling everything.
I think it could be great.
But let's go for the boss.
I think I may actually...
I'm gonna go look for a secret room.
Right here.
Haha!
Who's the man?
Destroy him.
And all his compadres.
Uh, we're done.
Let me see my items.
Am I happy with my items?
10th oil minus touch.
I'm not happy about that one.
I wonder if the reroll works in that way where it says, Okay, here's an act of contrition.
This is an angel item.
Therefore, this will be rerolled into another angel item.
Because if that's the case, then I really like this.
This one is practically useless now, right?
Spider mod is gonna be sad to lose.
Dude, I'm doing it.
I'm doing it.
No pussy!
Okay.
Death's touch.
Alright.
Mom's pearls.
Rubber cement.
What's that?
Tears bounce off of enemies and up?
Okay, nice.
Box.
Okay, that's useless for me.
Scapular.
Okay, so this one is an angel item.
When damage down to the last half of heart automatically gain a soul heart.
Okay.
Seraphim.
Oh, we're actually 2 out of 3 on these.
Breakfast.
Stuy.
Bolt.
We get to keep that one.
Oh, sharp key!
Jumper cables.
Hey, you know what?
Hey, I like it!
Kinda slow going here, but you know.
Just gotta pump up those tier numbers.
Right now, those are rookie numbers.
Wait, where did this guy come from?
Burp?
Hey!
Huh?
That chest wasn't there last time I was there, I promise you.
Okay, let's go.
It's time for floor number 5.
Because I can count.
Don't be jelly.
Wait, so hold on.
This key thing...
consumes a key to launch.
The key damages and pierces.
You can also open the first lock or destroy the first obstacle it collides with.
Right.
Okay.
I don't think I'm gonna do that very much.
Oh god, I'm trying to dodge these stupid ass shots!
I hated animate objects.
Burp?
More lock for me.
Oh shit, I don't like this.
No!
We're so close with the buffer.
I think we're done.
Not these guys again.
No!
It's over!
Buffer gone.
Angel chances in the toilet.
Horrible.
Yep.
Dude, I need some tears.
And then it's gonna be great.
I guess we'll go in here now.
It was!
Show me what's good, brother.
Wait, what is it with this thing here?
You can't get in there.
Linger Bean.
Crying makes me toot.
Firing for four seconds releases a small fart cloud.
The cloud increases in size and decreases in damage.
Okay.
No, it doesn't.
Maybe it didn't work down there.
Am I... What?
Firing for four seconds releases a small fart cloud.
Okay, it does work.
I feel like that's more than four, but okay.
Wish I could fly.
I kind of like this kind of attack I have here.
Like, it's a huge projectile.
Like, it is dope, man.
Yo!
Like a reaper thingy.
A scythe, you know?
These enemies are so weird, I don't understand them.
Let's see what's in here.
Imagine I get conjoined with this.
There's a high chance we get that.
That means we're going to be shooting way more of these bad boys and they're going to bounce all over the place.
Shit!
That's reeeeally bad!
Like, really bad!
That may actually have been game ending bad.
That pill.
I'm not joking.
Make up for it with a good pill.
Give me more pills.
Okay, save the rest.
No, absolutely not.
It is what it is.
At least we get damage from taking damage.
It makes it feel better.
Honestly though, like, having less tears, I don't even feel the difference.
Because it was so slow before.
I barely feel it.
Time for a treasure room.
Be good to me.
Show me the tears.
Okay, here we go.
Scat!
No!
Eww!
That's horrible.
Ananimate object?
I'm going to take damage from that.
Maybe.
Or not.
Mom's bracelet.
Wait, that's actually good.
I like that more.
Can I...
I'm just going to pick up the guy here, but I can also re-roll.
Not too much though.
Fifteen.
Okay, I'll be back.
Shouldn't have donated all that money.
Do I have infinite range or something?
Like, they just keep going and going and going like...
I can just sit in a corner, actually.
I'm playing billiard.
Pool.
I'm sort of angling like this.
You see how... Yeah, that's awesome.
I'm going to shoot him like that.
I'm going to angle off the wall like that.
Okay, there's not infinite range, but it's close.
Not bad.
The belt.
Okay.
Not too bad.
I take that.
I'm sure we can scrounge up, like, six more coins.
In fact, I'm pretty sure I can.
Let's blow that up.
Fucking cluster bombs.
No coins, unfortunately.
Oh, this is going to be good.
Oh, the sides are so good at that.
Wonderful.
There we go!
The money, baby!
We got the money!
Money, money, money, money, money!
We got it, we got it, we got it.
Did you see how it bounced off one wall and hit the other guy?
So it actually hit both.
Even though they were on opposite sides of the room.
Very nice, very nice.
Are you not dead?
Lovely.
Absolutely lovely.
This could be a secret.
In fact, I think it is.
How am I so good at this game?
I actually surprised myself.
I may actually write a book, you know.
All the secrets to Isaac.
Purchase to get to know everything there is to know.
Gives a copy of the last pill taken.
Hey, okay.
I guess I'll keep that for now.
In case I find something extraordinary.
And I think we're done.
No, no.
Shop and then done.
We're going to go...
Oh, we can even re-roll again, guys.
Because we are mega rich.
Give me that.
Red candle.
Oh no, what is that?
Launches the directional attack.
I'm not feeling it.
Wait, I wonder...
So, this question mark here, right?
It's technically on a pedestal in here.
I wonder if that gets re-rolled when I do this.
No.
Oh no, we don't have enough money, but do we?
We don't!
We do!
Oh, I didn't mean to do that, actually.
But okay, that's fine.
A deck of cards.
Wait, what the fuck?
There's a spider in here.
Two red hearts.
Wait, what's the...
Wait, what is that?
I don't understand what's happening right now.
That's a random card.
I mean, that's good.
But I don't know, like...
Yeah, I guess I'll keep it.
Yeah, it's fine.
Let's just leave.
Dude, my stomach is rumbling.
I'm extra hungry for some reason.
Hungry for victory?
We're now on the mom floor.
Hold up!
Emergency!
We need teleport card.
Teleport.
Maximum focus on teleport.
Open your mouth, man!
Thank you.
What the hell was that?
That's some bullshit right there.
Terrible item.
But I like that it gives me health, so it's actually a good item.
Only redeeming quality is that it's a decent item.
This one's gonna be tough.
Yeah, I knew it.
I knew I wouldn't be able to do this room without taking damage.
I could consider this.
Let's see what we find.
I can use the 48-hour energy to spawn a bunch of cards.
Why is this guy blue?
Wait a minute, I'm spawning pills instead of cards.
No, I'm not.
I am spawning cards.
Do it.
Yeah.
Not bad.
We even get a buffer.
A little too late, though.
Another one.
Wow.
Good.
Wait, how am I already at max energy again?
I must have some crazy shit going on here.
Is it that one?
It may be jumper cables.
Oh, this one as well.
Dude, I have a crazy energy recharge configuration.
The moon as well, I like it.
Look how fast I'm charging this thing.
For real, though, I need more tears.
I would love to find that item that gives me like a million tears, but reduces my damage.
You know, I always find that item at the worst times and never at the right time.
I have mind.
Maybe if I come back later with some money.
No!
I got a key here.
Let's go do the boss, I guess.
Oh, no, actually.
No, no, not yet.
Not yet.
We want to save.
The Hank man.
Actually, hold on.
Hank man is kind of sick.
I kind of like Hank man.
There's a place where I need to fly.
Where was that place?
Also, let me use this now.
Judgment.
Okay.
The Hierophant.
Damn.
Give me that.
There was a room where flying was absolutely needed.
I'm going to trust my instincts and remember that I actually got that right.
I tried to hit all three.
But it actually turned out to work.
Oh, there's going to be battery recharge here, guys.
Oh, yeah.
Not bad.
Close.
No,
what the... came out of nowhere.
The Hierophant again.
Where's my teleporter?
I need teleportation.
Open up.
The Hank man, let's do...
Ah, there it is.
Nice.
I was looking for you.
I guess we can do that now.
We're going north.
I'm going to kill this son of a gun real fast and come back.
Full check, everything else check, check, check, go.
Oh.
I'm losing too much HP.
This is bad.
There we go, there we go.
I think I'll take the negative, thank you.
I'll be taking that one.
And...
Call me a fool!
Twice that's on you and once is on me or something.
There's a saying.
More energy, wow.
Actually kind of cool.
Two of spades is... what is that one?
Doubles the keys, I like it.
But do I like it more than this?
Maybe not actually, not yet.
There's one room where flying was freaking mandatory.
Maybe I'm imagining things.
Let me see, is there a chest or somewhere on the map?
Not really.
We have 12 coins, we could go to the shop and maybe buy...
a little something, something.
Dang it.
Okay, so we found a secret room there.
What about fight room?
Probably closed.
Let's see what's going on.
Yeah, it's closed.
Okay, well...
I think it's time.
I'm gonna keep the hanged man.
Go.
Let's do it.
Mossel Liam, we lost a lot of damage.
A lot of that damage came from the Samson effect.
So we're kind of weak now.
We need something drastic here, like a drastic change.
This is not gonna cut it, you know?
I can't reach this guy, like what's going on here?
Like, how the fuck am I gonna reach this dude?
With a bomb maybe?
Insanity.
Brutal room.
A dead end as well.
Oh my god.
Oh my god!
It's so dark, is that...
What is that?
I thought it was a converter, man.
Get in.
Motherfucker, he pushed my bomb away.
No, that's like a transistor or something.
Oh my god, please.
Where am I taking damage?
I must have walked into some fire.
Old capacitor.
Active items no longer gain charge from completing rooms.
20% chance of spawn on the old battery.
Eh...
No.
Bombs are key.
Eh... yeah.
Sick.
What about tears up though?
Can we get that up?
I don't like the darkness here.
The fool.
In case I need it.
I mean, I would say the build is very, very mid right now.
It's not bad, it's not good, you know?
This room seems impossible, I don't know how to do this.
Okay, that's one way to do it, actually.
I figured it out.
Still very difficult.
And we lost our angel chairs, of course!
Oh no, wait, I can't go back!
I done goofed.
Well, this one's gonna be hard to do.
How can you have spent our savings?
Holy...
Rush the key.
Please stand to find the keys.
What do I currently have?
Yeah, we don't want that anymore.
That's fine.
Calm down.
Whoa!
Wait, what?
Is that from the current floor that I never got to experience?
Strength?
I think I wanna keep that, actually.
Wait, another one?
Oh, and it's a different one, okay.
Apple of Sodom.
Chance to convert a red heart into blue spiders instead of healing.
No thanks.
That's bad.
I will take this card, though.
Uh, sure.
Nothing exciting there.
Oh, I can't shoot, I can't shoot!
Oh
no, dude, it's over for me.
We're totally back.
It's
okay.
Damn!
Amazing dodging.
I'm definitely getting to town on this.
Very unlucky.
And now it's dead.
Like, I don't even have a great active right now.
I feel like I'm not prepared for combat.
I'm just not.
The Hermit.
What was that one again?
To the shop.
Wait, where's that guy taking me here, then?
Oh, okay, I was in the shop, that's funny.
I feel like I need a strategy where I take damage on purpose.
Like, I need that towards the end of this.
But I don't think I can make it happen.
This one is interesting.
This is either amazing or absolutely terrible.
Well, you know, actually...
Hold on, let me see it in a bigger room.
Let me see.
It's a lot of more tiers, like, this is like 0.58 tiers, it's gonna be quite significant.
I think it may actually be good.
Yeah, I like it.
We need damage.
It's just gonna be a little bit weird to aim it.
You know, the confusion that comes from having this sort of weird aim here could actually be bad enough to not get it, you know?
Like, it's really difficult to figure out where I'm shooting when they're all just flying all over the place.
Okay, we're done here.
I'm gonna keep it.
I believe in it.
We're gonna have some time to practice it, right?
Oh, the magician is really good, guys.
We're gonna have homing tears.
I'm gonna save it for the last boss.
Trust it'll be good.
Keep exploring.
I need health.
I need, like, more health than what I have.
This ain't enough.
Oh, wait, what is that gonna be?
Oh, range.
Sure.
Yes, that's what I'm talking about, baby.
More of that.
Whatever.
Oh, god.
Are we done in here?
Not quite.
Oh.
And that was that.
I will need to play really well to do this.
Okay, and some healing.
Wait, I lost my blue heart.
Okay, fuck you then.
Lil Spewer?
Remember that charges and releases puke attacks that create creep with different effects.
Sponsored random pill when picked up.
Hey, okay, okay.
I like it.
Did we just actually get puberty?
No, that was not, like, three, right?
Look at all that puke.
I grew up in my scheme.
That's two damage.
No, I'm gonna keep the magician.
The magician is the one that's gonna really, you know, is it though?
Is it actually?
Hold on.
I'm starting to think because the bosses I'm gonna be facing, it's not gonna be a problem to hit them.
I don't think.
Unless, oh, actually, when we go into the flappy bird section of the boss, I don't know if it's gonna bounce off the top or the lava down below.
It may actually not bounce.
I'm gonna keep it.
Uh, no.
A hermit.
Dude, I love finding pills.
More pills.
Oh god.
That's not good.
Cheeky.
No hearts, though.
Guys, we may be in trouble here.
I don't have a lot of HP.
I don't have a wafer.
I have no protections.
It's looking pretty bad.
I can't get in there.
Don't.
Shit.
Give me hearts.
No.
Come on.
I need like a health up or something.
Give me a health.
Oh, nice.
Oh, but magician.
No, we got it.
We got to take this.
Fuck yeah.
It's like really random.
Like where you find that?
Yeah, this guy just can't die.
I am always impressed at how much HP this man has every time I see him.
Sure, why not?
Oh, fuck off.
No.
No, what about health?
Blow him up.
Okay.
This way.
Dude, I think we're cooked.
Don't spike me.
Thank God.
Thank Jesus.
No, we're not religious in this family.
Religion is bad.
Look at mom.
We will thank the sun for giving us nourishment and energy for driving all life on earth.
The sun deserves our praise.
Definitely.
No, fucking inanimate objects.
I swear to God.
Wait, what?
Actually, grants increased all stats.
Think about it.
During the fight, I don't need to...
what do you call it?
Use a card, right?
So by having full energy, I think it's actually better than the Ouroboros worm.
Especially because I don't have the magician now and I don't know if anything is going to bounce anyway and...
you know, so fuck it.
I say let's do it.
I do love the predictability of the shots now.
Well, the easier predictability.
Okay, let's go.
Huge.
Any heart we can get right now is big.
What the fuck was that?
What hit me?
No.
Yes.
That's what I needed.
There's too much.
No, that's horrible as well.
Damn, this man has HP.
Wait, does strength do anything?
It heals, actually.
You're kidding me.
Are they bouncing off the wall as well, like his projectiles?
They are.
Dude, what's happening?
It's over.
I don't know what's hitting me.
It's too hard.
Oh, my God, bro.
Come on, lovers.
The sun!
Massive.
We're back.
Oh, wait, that was a cracked rock.
Nice.
We're back in business.
It was so over, but now we're so back.
Amazing.
Keep exploring.
Puke on him.
I'm guessing the puke is going to be unusable or useless against the last boss.
Ancient recall?
What was that?
Random cards.
That's huge.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah!
Sponsor key.
No.
Actually, no.
That's bad for me.
Puke on him.
The fool.
I say no to that.
Another blue heart, dude.
Are we actually back?
I think we're back for realsies.
Now to find the light.
There it is.
Wow.
We are so freaking back.
This guy is crazy.
I hate this guy.
Like, how do you dodge this guy without taking damage?
It is impossible.
Okay, actually, stay at max range.
That's the way to do it.
I figured it out.
Just stay at max range.
Destroy the evil flame.
At pill we haven't tried?
Oh.
That's the exit.
Here, another one of these.
I like these ones.
Maximum gambling.
Are you kidding me?
Not a single?
Whoa.
Toilet roll.
Do I like that, actually?
Hold on.
No.
I like my current one.
No!
Man, these things suck.
At least right now.
Shiny rock, uh, nothing.
Another Hankman, you gotta be kidding me.
Whatever.
Hey, he wants keys.
I got you, friend.
I can even go grab a bomb's keys if I have that on this floor.
It may be the last floor.
Okay, that's not good for me.
Ooh, here we go.
Shit.
Okay.
I mean, I like his style.
Okay, okay.
Man!
Okay, let's see if we have bombs or keys.
I think it may be the one I see on the map right here.
Nope, that's also the Hankman.
Damn, that must have been last floor.
I guess I can go back and blow him up.
Wait a minute, two of clubs?
That's bombs.
Okay, I mean, yeah, okay.
Let's go down here.
It's gonna be energy for me.
Wait, what did I just find there?
Blueheart?
Wants coins?
I guess I can give him some.
Maybe I can give him some keys and I can give that to the other guy.
There we go.
More.
Bandy pack.
Sure.
Very cool.
And that was that.
Wait, I see something on the map there.
What is that item in there?
Oh, it's the guy, isn't it?
It's the guy.
Here, have my key.
Can't open it now.
Shit, that feels bad.
Whatever.
It's okay.
No, no, I can't open the chest now!
Oh, no way.
Be a key.
I
have so many bombs.
Oh, this one.
Hello,
Samson.
Oh, he looks like a strong man.
Like Hercules or something.
Moms contacts.
Hey, that's gonna take us to three out of three.
But the problem is, it doesn't do anything.
Like it makes this knife and it's fucking useless.
It doesn't do nothing.
It's absolutely trash.
All right, we really need to up our game here to win this one because we are not in a great position damage wise or build wise.
We are kinda fucked.
We may need to utilize bombs to great effect here.
Let's see how it goes.
Wish me luck.
Dogma.
Bomb for you.
What the heck, man?
Hey, I found a key.
That's kinda cool.
Oh, I can't stand on the creep, apparently.
I can't tell difference between mine and his.
Donate, donate, donate.
We're dead, man.
We're dead.
It's over.
There is no way we're making this one.
Where is he?
Oh, there he is.
Also, the problem is we don't even have full energy on the active.
So the trinket does nothing.
Oh, my goodness.
I deal no damage.
I have no damage.
I need more tears.
Jesus Christ.
Wow.
I think we're done.
Oh, wait, we have full health?
What?
We're back.
69 bombs.
Oh, wait, the hearts are just gonna fall.
I lost my mantle.
My damage is so bad.
Okay, okay, not bad, not bad.
Haha, look at this beggar.
What?
That hit me straight in the face.
That's crazy.
Bombs from above.
What's happening?
Oh, right, right, next one.
Oh, crap.
Oh, wow.
I'm in deep shit.
Come on, son.
I need the sun.
Lovers?
Grab him.
I got him, I got him.
I got the lovers.
Come on, baby.
Sides versus scythes.
What the fuck?
I'm scared.
Nice.
Good shit.
Come on, baby.
Keep it up, keep it up.
I have a friend.
We can't walk into him, though.
That's a bad idea.
Grab
the heart!
We got it.
Bomb.
I missed.
What is he doing now?
Bro, what?
Bombs.
More bombs.
Keep throwing bombs.
The sun.
Boom, baby.
Temperance.
Donate blood, donate blood, donate.
Wow.
That was crazy.
What do you say to that one, huh?
I mean, come on.
That was so clutch.
Can't tell me it wasn't.
Dude, the deck of cards carried me in the end.
I was on like half a heart at one point.
How crazy was that?
My heart is racing.
It is in my throat right now.
Holy crap.
Good script today.
Thank you, thank you.
Praise the sun, indeed.
Praise the sun.
Oh, man.
The last one was so cinematic.
I agree.
There were so many ups and downs.
So many we are so dead.
We are so back moments.
Crazy.
Dude, the fact that this game can get my heart pumping like that, even after... I don't even know how many hours I have in this game at this point.
150 hours is insane.
Wow.
Acting for this dream went great.
Thank you.
You can give me the Oscar now.
Feeling like Praise the sun is going to be the title.
You know what?
Actually, that's a great title.
I haven't thought about the title yet.
But that's going to be the title.
Either that or something related to gambling or cards.
Ace up my sleeve or something like that.
You know, that could be a good one too.
Because that really was the ace up the sleeve towards the end.
And yeah, and next time we have a new tainted character, guys.
We're going to experiment with.
It's going to be good.
What do you mean, plot armor, man?
I was fighting for my life.
The entire run.
I really poured blood, sweat and tears into that victory, okay?
That didn't come easy.
But yeah, you're right.
That was a bit of plot armor here and there.
Just a couple of times.
You 100%ed Isaac today?
It's my turn now?
Damn.
I don't know if I'm ever going to get to 100%.
That's a little crazy.
I will keep playing until I don't have fun anymore.
And if that happens at 100%, then so be it.
If not, then not.
Scapula clutch, like five times.
I don't even remember what that does.
I remember getting it, but I don't remember what it does.
But I'm sure you're right.
He's from Greenland again.
I heals you back from Denmark.
My brother.
The soul heart when reaching.
Oh, the soul heart when reaching half heart.
That's right.
Yeah, I was wondering actually how I had that, but it makes sense.
But honestly, the real MVP here was getting fully healed when I got to the last boss after dogma.
Because I thought, oh, I'm dead.
There's no way I'm doing the last thing without taking any damage with this low of a DPS.
So just getting all that was great.
Yeah,
I like the game.
The game is pretty good.
I would say Binding of Isaac in terms of, you know, what it's trying to do.
This is a 10 out of 10 game.
Like this is a 10 out of 10 roguelike game.
It is the perfect roguelike for me so far.
And that's coming from someone who is a mega hater of bullet hells, which this game kinda is at times.
So that's very high praise.
Okay.
It
is so good.
Yeah, it is a bullet hell, but yeah.
Guy who only died to hush once.
Is that true?
Did I only die once to hush?
We need to do more speedruns to do more hush.
Actually, it's been a while since I did some speedruns.
We should do that.
Go slap his ass.
Dude, we should go.
We should start speedrunning with the new Azazel.
With the guy who goes with his sword.
You know, we gotta speedrun with all these characters.
That sounds like fun.
You haven't played it.
Yeah, I haven't played Azazel in a long time, man.
I've been detoxing.
It's time to get back into it.
Dude, Azazel 2 is so much fun, Ghost.
Like, the fact that you can do the close-up attack and then you combo it into the long range is like genius design.
It flows so well.
Such a good character.
And I only played him once or twice.
And I already knew this guy was gonna be special, you know?
Yeah, Azazel tolerance break.
It's like when you haven't had ASMR in a while, you know, you go on a cold turkey for like a month.
And then you put on your best headphones, turn it all the way up, and you sit down just like the guy from American Psycho, you know, with his headphones on, and you just feel it.
It's called Tinkle Immunity.
You have a name for the flipside characters?
Well, I call them Tainted now, because all of you call them Tainted.
But I don't know what I would call them.
The dark version of them, I guess.
Tinkle Immunity?
Yeah, yeah.
So, like, not Tinkle with a K, Tinkle with a G.
Because ASMR gives you, like, a slight tinkle in the scalp, you know, and... yeah.
If you watch too much or listen to too much ASMR, you kind of get used to it, and it's not as special anymore.
Call them new characters?
Yeah, I guess you could call them whatever.
Alternate versions, Dark Side, Tainted.
Nasty characters.
Nasty Eulith.
Nasty Azazel.
I like that.
That's a good name.
Because they're nasty.
Especially Eulith.
Nasty Eulith is really nasty.
Fucked up characters is a good one, too.
He hasn't seen the nastiest yet.
Well, I can't imagine how it can get worse than Eulith, because that is just disgusting the way her, you know, thing opens up, and the thing comes out and it does the thing, you know?
Oh, I had no challenges in a while!
Shit, we gotta get back to that as well.
Could it be that I did a challenge that tilted me so much that I just forgot challenges existed?
I forgot what the last one was that I did.
Was there a really tilting challenge?
I forgot.
What was the last challenge I did?
I did a bunch in a row, and I kept winning, I remember.
Huh.
Fun fact is that on the final delirium fight on Bethany, you had cursed eyes and it didn't activate.
Really?
Oh shit!
I thought for sure I had lost it or something.
I was wondering.
Wait, how do you know?
Because I never checked my items, did I?
So how do you know?
Whenever I rerolled, I never checked my items after that.
Oh, it shows them on the side.
Oh!
Dude, I actually never look there.
I kinda wanna turn that off.
Oh, I guess it's better for you guys so you can see what I have.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Actually, let's keep it on so you guys can see it at least.
I mean, I knew they were there, I just never look at them, because it's useless for me to just look at them there.
I would rather look at them in my inventory so I can read about them at the same time, right?
Dude, my monitor is not that big.
It's 27 inches.
I used to have a 32 inch, that's a long time ago.
I swapped it out for a 27 inch.
I just like the increased pixel density on a bit smaller monitor.
Us pro Isaac players don't need descriptions.
Yeah, I guess that makes sense.
I guess you just look at an item and go, ah, that's not the one I need.
27 is honestly still a huge monitor, is it?
I'm not that close to it though, it's kinda far away from me.
I guess a 32 inch is like a gigantic one.
Which is one of the reasons that I swapped it back to a 27.
Yeah, 27 is like the sweet spot for me at least.
I used to be a 24-in-joyer too, Dasanti.
It was just a good mix.
But since I'm doing so much productivity stuff as well, like...
like editing things and having a bunch of windows open or doing some coding and stuff, it's so nice to have that extra real estate.
You don't even know how big yours is, Dawn?
You think yours is 27?
It's like a 10-year-old monitor that you never check because it still works or something.
Will you play Question Mark?
Actually, I was thinking of playing Question Mark today.
The blue boy.
Dude, I kinda wanna do that actually, and then try and unlock his version.
Dark Question Mark.
That's gonna be difficult though guys, that's gonna be a...
that's gonna be a tough one.
I'm gonna have to summon all the strength I can summon.
I'm gonna have to hire the best script writers.
I'm gonna need to acquire the most and bestest of the plot armor out there.
Otherwise, we're not gonna bring it home.
Nasty blue baby is so shitty.
Well, that's just your opinion, man.
I'm gonna form my own opinion on that.
The best script writers, yes.
After today's run, I believe in you.
Thank you.
Dude, that was so sick.
Actually, the best run to end it on.
I'm an opinion former, yes.
I form opinions.
I do that.
I've been known to do that.
Guys, I'm leaving.
Thank you so much for watching.
What a fantastic session.
How is this game still this much fun?
It's a mystery we will never get the answer to.
Edmund McMillan is a genius and he deserves all the praise.
And so do you guys.
Bye-bye.